<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <name>Empire Refactored: Outposts &amp; Settlements</name>
    <author>Matathias</author>
    <packageId>Matathias.EmpireRefVOE</packageId>
    <modVersion>0.3.15</modVersion>
    <supportedVersions><li>1.6</li></supportedVersions>
    <description>Empire and Vanilla Outposts Expanded - two of the oldest and, at least at one point in time, most popular mods to enable a semblence of 4X gameplay in Rimworld. Yet, they operate entirely independently of each other, with no integration whatsoever.

**Empire Refactored: Outposts &amp; Settlements** aims to rectify that. It adds numerous minor systems to tie VOE Outposts into Empire Refactored's gameplay systems:

- Defensive Outposts can auto-defend like Empire squads, and outposts in general are vulnerable to Empire raids (though such raids only resolve through auto-battles)
- Outposts, under the right conditoins, can be transformed into Empire settlements
- Empire settlements can send their taxes and tithes to a specific outpost, and can also be set to draw all necessary funds from an outpost's coffers
- Production and Science outposts can be linked to a settlement, providing a boost to that settlement's resource production instead of materials or raw research points
- Encampments accelerate the heal rate of Empire mercs in nearby settlements
- Outposts are included in Empire's road-building system, resulting in all of your outposts and settlements being connected</description>
    <incompatibleWith>
        <!-- Folded into this mod: its Town spawn-requirement config and planet-layer fix are now built in. -->
        <li>matathias.voetownscountoutposts</li>
    </incompatibleWith>
    <modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>Matathias.Empire</packageId>
            <displayName>Empire</displayName>
        </li>
        <li>
            <packageId>vanillaexpanded.outposts</packageId>
            <displayName>Vanilla Outposts Expanded</displayName>
        </li>
    </modDependencies>
    <loadAfter>
        <li>Matathias.Empire</li>
        <li>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</li>
        <li>vanillaexpanded.outposts</li>
        <li>Matathias.Empire.Specialists</li>
		<li>MrHydralisk.VOEPowerGrid</li>
		<li>Scorpio.VOEFactory</li>
		<li>MrHydralisk.VOEAdditionalOutposts</li>
    </loadAfter>
    <modIconPath IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">UI/Icons/EmpireLogo</modIconPath>
</ModMetaData>
